Spoon or sboon? An interesting thing about liaisons is that so much of it has to do
with whether a consonant is voiced or not. The key thing to remember is that the
vocal cords don't like switching around at the midpoint. If the first consonant is
voiced, the next one will be as well. If the first one is unvoiced, the second one
will sound unvoiced no matter what you do. For example, say the word spoon. Now say
the word spoon. Hear how they sound the same? This is why I'd like you to always
convert the preposition to, to duh when you're speaking English, no matter what
comes before it. In the beginning, to get you used to the concept, we made a
distinction between tuh and duh, but now that your schwa is in place, use the
single duh sound everywhere, except at the very beginning of a sentence. After a
voiced sound, he had to do it. After an unvoiced sound, he got to do it, at the
beginning of a sentence, to be or not to be. To have your liaisons tested, call 800
-457-4255.